{
    "labs": [
        {
            "name": "Simple File Commands",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display your current working directory.",
                    "answer": "pwd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Change to your home directory.",
                    "answer": "cd ~"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of your current directory.",
                    "answer": "ls"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display all files including hidden directories.",
                    "answer": "ls -a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display a long list of the contents of the current working directory.",
                    "answer": "ls -l"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the file types of the current working directory.",
                    "answer": "ls -F"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Return to your home directory.",
                    "answer": "cd ~"
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file.",
                    "answer": "cat /etc/default/keyboard"
                },
                {
                    "id": 9,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Under what circumstance must you refrain from using the cat command to view the contents of a file?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Never, you can always use cat.",
                        "b. You cannot cat executable files.",
                        "c. You cannot cat json files."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 10,
                    "type": "multi-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file and the '/etc/default/cron file",
                    "answers": [
                        "cat /etc/default/keyboard / /etc/default/cron",
                        "more /etc/default/keyboard /etc/default/cron"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "id": 11,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Display the contents of the '/etc/default/keyboard' file and the '/etc/default/cron' file using a single command.",
                    "answer": "more /etc/default/keyboard /etc/default/cron"
                },
                {
                    "id": 12,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the symbol '~' represent?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. It is a shortcut for the users home directory.",
                        "b. It doesn't have anything to do with linux.",
                        "c. It is a shortcut for the root directory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 13,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Complete the missing options to the mv command and their descriptions below:\n\n -i \n",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Ignore mode - ignores system advice.",
                        "b. Interactive mode - helps to prevent accidental overwriting.",
                        "c. Invalid option for mv."
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 14,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "\n -r \n",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. Removes redundant files at new location.",
                        "b. Invalid option for mv.",
                        "c. Includes the content of a directory, including the contents of all subdirectories when you copy a directory."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "File Redirection and Pipes",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Type the who command and use redirection, a pipe or appending in order to see the output when using the sort command from a single command line entry.",
                    "answer": "who | sort"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What type of operation enables you to send the output of a command directly to a file?",
                    "answer": "redirection"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "single_answer",
                    "prompt": "Which operation allows you to send the output of a command to the bottom of a file (if that file already exists)?",
                    "answer": "appending"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Unix Meta-characters, Filenames and How to Use Man Pages",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "From the command line list only file or directory names that begin with the letter 'b'.",
                    "answer": "ls b*"
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "From your home directory use the “?” metacharacter to find an file or directory that ends with 'eans'.",
                    "answer": "ls ?eans"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "If you issue the command ls ?* what is the result? Why do you think you get that result?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. ",
                        "b. You will see a recursive listing of everything in the directory and all subsequent subdirectories.",
                        "c. "
                    ],
                    "answer": "b"
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What special characters must be avoided when creating a file name?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. / * & %",
                        "b. ",
                        "c. "
                    ],
                    "answer": "a"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What command do you enter to obtain help on how to use a command?",
                    "answer": "man"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "What does the whatis command do?",
                    "answers": [
                        "a. ",
                        "b. ",
                        "c. It gives a one-line description of the command, but omits any information about options etc."
                    ],
                    "answer": "c"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "What command can you enter to find the name of the command if you aren’t sure of the exact name?",
                    "answer": "apropos"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Security",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "table",
                    "prompt": "Fill in the permission sets and write the 3 digit octal number that represents the permission sets in the format:",
                    "format":"owner, group, other, octal-value",
                    "values": ["group", "skel", "motd"],
                    "answers": ["rw-, r--, r--, 644", "rwx, r-x, r-x, 755", "rwx, rwx, rwx, 777"]
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Create a new file and a new directory – what are the permissions?",
                    "answer": "rw- r-- r--"
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "multi-choice",
                    "prompt": "Distinguish between the symbolic and octal modes.",
                    "answers": ["c. Symbolic uses symbols as seen above there are symbolic permissions rw- r—r—the octal equivalent is 644."]
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using symbolic permissions add write permissions for the group to the /etc/skel file.",
                    "answer": "chmod g+a /etc/skel"
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using octal mode, change permissions on the motd file to –rwxrw----.",
                    "answer": "chmod 740 /etc/motd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Using octal mode add write permissions for other on the file named group.",
                    "answer": "chmod 646 /etc/group"
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "single-answer",
                    "prompt": "Identify the UID and the GID for the group file. Which command did you use?",
                    "answer": "ls –n motd"
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 9,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 10,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 11,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 12,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Other useful UNIX commands",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 8,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "name": "Variables",
            "tasks": [
                {
                    "id": 1,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 2,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 3,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 4,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 5,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 6,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                },
                {
                    "id": 7,
                    "type": "",
                    "prompt": "",
                    "answer": ""
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}